September 14th, 2017

Shopify Inc.

Toronto, ON

RE: Developer Intern - Winternship 2018, Shopify

Dear Katie,

I am writing to express my interest in the Developer Intern - Wintership 2018 position. I am a third year student in Honours Bachelor of Computer Science (co-op) at the University of Waterloo and Honours Bachelor of Business Administration at Wilfrid Laurier University Double Degree program. Richard Hugessen, a current developer intern at Shopify Plus (Waterloo), recommended I apply to Shopify and believes I would be a good fit for this position. I work with him on the Laziridis Students' Society (LazSoc) technology development team.

My co-op experience and activities have provided me with a variety of software development skills. My most recent projects include creating a chat feature for the LazSoc website using a rails websockets gem and Angular to render messages. I am currently working on implementing a feature where business students can easily connect with each other to network and talk about their past experiences.

In my most recent co-op term at Capco, I developed features based off client specifications for a big 5 bank's iOS app using Swift and web app front end using Angular. I am also a Double Degree Mentor, where I mentor first year computer science and business double degree students on co-op, academics, and extra-curriculars. I am certain I can apply and enhance my skills at Shopify.

This position particularly interests me because of the testimonials from your previous interns. Solving real problems, shipping real projects, and seeing personal growth are the attributes of my ideal internship. In this position, I'll be able to make a worldwide impact on the thousands of merchants that use the Shopify platform.

Thank you for considering my application for this position. I am confident that my skills will be valuable in this position. Please feel free to contact me by phone at 647-504-3042 or by email at riyaz.shaikh33@icloud.com.

Sincerely,

Riyaz Shaikh

Riyaz Shaikh

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technology Consultant Capco

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017 Toronto, ON

- Worked with backend services to develop front end features based off client specifications using Angular for the web app and Swift for the iOS app of a big 5 bank
- Presented a pitch to Capco partners for a ML (classification) capability to enhance the **UX** of retail banking consumers

Web Developer

Interactive Computer Solutions

May 2016 - Aug 2016 Vaughan, ON

- Led design and development of client invoicing product using PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JS
- Implemented real-time editing functionality using web sockets
- Built an image and pdf processor to improve productivity of the project manager when dealing with client requests using JS

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Web Developer

Laziridis Students' Society

Oct 2016 - Present Wilfrid Laurier University

- Developing new features for the LazSoc online infrastructure (RESTful API, mobile & web app, social network) for 3000+ business students using Ruby on Rails and Angular
- Implemented networking feature that allows students to easily connect and share their experiences with each other
- Built invoicing component that digitized physical paper experience

Web Developer

Sep 2014 – Apr 2015 North Park Secondary School - Student Activity Council (SAC)

Led the development of the SAC website with features such as a CMS, newsfeed, polls, and calendars using PHP, MySQL, JS

PROJECTS

Sorcery — School Project (project grade: 99.2%)

Jul 2017

Used many **OOP** techniques and design patterns in **C++** to develop a card game played through the command line

Find me a Job — https://git.io/vi7Kn

Developed a platform in assisting tech job seekers to find the jobs that match the skillset on their resume at Hack the North

ASL Jesters — https://git.io/vznIE

Nov 2015

Developed an application to help teach American Sign Language using Leap Motion and its JS API at Hack Western riyaz.shaikh@uwaterloo.ca github.com/riyaz33 riyazshaikh.me

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Honours Bachelor of Computer Science (Co-op) 2015 - 2020

Wilfrid Laurier University

Honours Bachelor of Business Administration 2015 - 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/ **Frameworks**

Ruby on Rails, JavaScript (Angular, ¡Query, Node.js), PHP (Laravel 4 & 5), SQL, Swift 3, C/C++, Python, Java

Software/Tools

Git, MySQL, Xcode, Eclipse, Sketch, JustInMind

OTHER ACTIVITIES

- VP Finance, UW Cricket Club
- Double Degree Mentor
- Hackathon participant
- Cricket, Volleyball intramurals

AWARDS

University of Waterloo

 President's Scholarship (2015)

North Park Secondary School

- Computer Science Award (2015)
- Athlete of the Year (2013, 2014, and 2015)